santafenewmexican.com 2011-10-11

# Registration information, privacy policy and terms of use - The Santa Fe New Mexican

**About registration**

When you visit certain sections of our site, such as local news, more than twice, you will be presented with a "Register for free" page. We ask you to create an account with about eight pieces of information. 

**How is this information used?**

SantaFeNewMexican.com's primary goal in collecting personal information is to maintain a free site by attracting advertisers. By knowing a little about you, SantaFeNewMexican.com is able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content, and hence better service, to you. In our role of delivering targeted advertisements, SantaFeNewMexican.com plays the middleman. Advertisers give us an advertisement and tell us the type of audience they want to reach (for example, males over 35 years old). SantaFeNewMexican.com will soon be able to display an ad to readers meeting just those criteria. This kind of ad targeting can be done with banner ads as well as promotional e-mail. 

The advertiser never has access to individual account information. Only SantaFeNewMexican.com has access to individuals' accounts. You will only receive special offers via e-mail from SantaFeNewMexican.com (never directly from advertisers in any case) if you have indicated in your account preferences that you would like to receive them. You can change your account preferences at any time. 

Another reason for registration is to provide better security and online community management for the increasing use of the forums. Our forum community is growing, and requiring people to stand behind their comments with their full, real names, creates better online behavior and participation. Although your name will be attached to your comment, your e-mail or other information will not.

SantaFeNewMexican.com does research on our readers' demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, during a promotion, from our server log files or from surveys. We do this to better understand and serve our readers. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. SantaFeNewMexican.com may share this aggregated data with advertisers or business partners.

**_In general, we make no attempt to associate this information with a reader's identity.  
_**  
However, we must know your identity for certain areas of the site to work properly. For example, if we decide to make an area of our site available only to print subscribers, then we would need to verify your status as a subscriber. If you respond to an online poll, a cookie prevents you from voting twice. If you send us a message, we use your e-mail address to respond, and we save the exchange. If you ask us to send headlines via e-mail, we save your e-mail address, and we may use it to contact you about other services of The New Mexican, Inc. 

**_We will not share any lists of e-mail addresses or other personal information with any third party._**

In any such e-mail from us, we will provide a way for you to "opt out" or choose to decline to receive promotional e-mail from us. We may occasionally find a third-party offer in which we believe you might be interested and may send you information, but we will not provide your e-mail address to the third party. 

We may also offer various surveys on the site. If the survey is a news survey or about service satisfaction, we will not share that information. Certain other surveys and contests are promotional in nature, and are often sponsored by or hosted and run by our advertisers. 

In such cases, we disclose that we collect and may share the information you provide to enter the contest or complete the survey with the advertiser. Of course, you will always have the choice of whether to enter the contest or complete such a survey, and therefore you will control the decision about sharing your information. 

**How can I access, edit, or modify my personal information at SantaFeNewMexican.com?**

You may edit your account information at any time by using your e-mail address on record with us and password. If you have forgotten your password, click "Forgot Password?"  to have your password sent to you.

**What security measures does SantaFeNewMexican.com use to protect your personal data?**

Your SantaFeNewMexican.com account information is password-protected so that you and only you have access to this personal information. You may edit your account information by logging in with your e-mail and password. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. SantaFeNewMexican.com will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited e-mail. Also remember to sign out of your SantaFeNewMexican.com account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, SantaFeNewMexican.com cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

**Note to parents and children:**

We fully support the intent of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, which forbids the collection of personally identifiable information about children under the age of thirteen without the express written permission of their parents. We ask that children do not submit any information about themselves. Anyone using this Site or the Services warrants and promises that they are 13 years of age or older. 

Some of the content on our site, including advertising, is provided directly from web servers owned and operated by third parties, and we do not control, and cannot be held responsible for, their use of any information they may collect.   

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>[  
](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

We do not routinely disclose any of our individual reader information to third parties. We may disclose this information in special cases when we have reason to believe that doing so is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) the rights or property of The New Mexican, Inc. or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. We may also disclose information to third parties when we believe in good faith that we are required by law to do so, or as otherwise provided in the Site's Terms of Use.

**A last word on internet privacy:**

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example in the forums, through email, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online.
